hello
hi and welcome back to the channel
someone on Instagram asked me in a DM to
do caramel Sutra by Ben and Jerry so
that's what we're gonna do
so caramel Sutra what is it it is half
tub caramel ice cream half tub chocolate
ice cream with chocolate pieces with a
really sticky Caramel Core
cold ice creams at home take some work
so if you're ready let's go
[Music]
we're going to start with the caramel
ice cream this is nice and easy and I'm
gonna use a really really good
ingredient here
which is sosa dolce de leche powder
so if you don't have that then I'll give
you an alternative in the description
but for now we're going to put our milk
in the pan we're going to add in our
sugars which has got our stabilizer in
there and then add in our dolce de leche
powder which is in place of the milk
powder White's all combined you can take
it off the heat pop it in a container
add in your cream and then put that in
the fridge to chill down for four to
five hours
foreign
[Music]
we're going to work on the chocolate ice
cream half
and for this one it's a very simple kind
of box standard chocolate ice cream I've
gone with a lower fat content cocoa
powder from design really nice flavor 10
fat content much in the same way as any
other chocolate ice cream start with
your milk add in your sugars with your
stabilizer your milk powder finally add
in your cocoa powder and make sure it's
completely dissolved into your base
might take a while if you do struggle
with things like that I recommend you
combine your milk powder your cocoa
powder and your sugar all together stir
that and then put that all in your milk
together it will dissolve much easier
once that has all completely dissolved
you're going to take it off the heat put
it in a container again add in your
cream give it a nice stir make sure it's
all completely combined and then put
that one in the fridge to show down
[Music]
onto the caramel bits now obviously your
ice cream bases are in the fridge for a
good few hours because you know that's
just how long they bloody take to cool
down caramel takes a while to make we're
going to start with a wet caramel so
that means we're going to add our sugar
and some water into a pan and we're
going to start to bring those up to
temperature what that temperature is
I'll put a link to Sugar temperature
scales in the description below but
really if you're doing this at home all
you need to be aware of is the color so
you're looking for a deep amber color
once it's at that stage you're going to
turn the heat off add in your butter be
careful because it will spit
and then once the butter is completely
melted into the sugar liquid you're
going to add in glucose liquid
help with the freezing point depression
and make sure that you get a really
sticky caramel in your ice cream then
once your glucose is melted into the
base you're going to finally add the
cream make sure it's nicely stirred in
dissolved and everything is emulsified
and then pop the whole thing in a
container to chill down to fridge
[Music]
okay
onto the cherny journey bit we're going
to start with the chocolate ice cream so
get that one in your machine going
whilst it's training you're going to
take some of your semi-sweet chocolate
it's a 50 56 chocolate get it chopped up
and you're going to put it in a little
pot because when your chocolate ice
cream is almost ready you're going to
add all of that in and make sure it's
nicely combined and then you're going to
take a good two to three large spoonfuls
of the ice cream and put it in your tub
but you're only going to put it on one
half
you're going to keep the tub on the side
and you're going to put some cling film
or plastic wrap over the top put the lid
on and store it in the freezer on its
side
you're going to leave it in there
probably for about three quarters of an
hour and do that with all the tubs so
all your chocolate ice cream gets loaded
into their respective Tubs on the side
in the freezer now we're going to move
on to the next stage
so after three quarters of an hour in
the freezer with the chocolate ice cream
half you're going to churn your caramel
ice cream and there's no add-ins in
there so straight caramel and once it
gets to the stage you're going to take
out your ice cream machine you're going
to start taking your tubs out the
freezer and pop the caramel into the
other half of the top again tap it down
make sure those voids are filled pops
and cling film shrink wrap over the top
and pop them back into the freezer
upright this time
so after a few hours you're gonna need
to keep an eye on the ice cream because
you don't want it to go too hard in the
freezer now I fell asleep
completely forgot to do this stage so I
had to do it the day after that was a
massive mistake on my behalf so this is
what I had to contend with
and along with that I also threw away
the tool that I use for doing chords you
know just one why not make life harder
for yourself when you can and I managed
to find a
semi-transparent or semi-rigid tube to
use to core out the ice cream this was
not going well
after leaving it to soften up for 30
minutes on the counter I finally managed
to get the tube into the middle of the
tub and was able to load the caramel in
now if you do this the same day after an
hour or two in the freezer you'll be
fine you can just push your cylindrical
tube into your ice cream tub everything
else will push out the way and you can
load the caramel in don't do what I'm
doing here because it just makes a
bloody mess
anyway let's see what it turned out like
you a lot of parts are doing cold ice
creams you know Ben and Jerry's have got
all the toys that you could ever imagine
for doing this you know they they do two
different fillers actually it's one
that's combined into two nozzles two
heads and they put the thing in and it
releases the ice cream exactly the same
way then it got another one with the
caramel that goes into the middle of
those ice creams they're still
relatively soft to this stage it all
does it in one it goes down a thing they
put the lid on done finished you can't
do that at home you don't have that at
home so when kylan on Instagram asked me
to make this ice cream I was like I've
done cold ice creams before no worries
let's just bash this one out done yeah
I up
so let's see what it turned out like and
and we'll go from there
I mean scooping scoopage
it's not too bad
I've done worse
it's got a nice Caramel Core the the
caramel ice cream it was I you know I'm
a spoon liquor when I make an ice cream
I will eat all the remnants that's in
the ice cream machine why not
but the color of the chocolate ice cream
is good lots of chocolate flecks nice
core let's eat some of this shall we
[Music]
that caramel let me let me get it out of
the cupboard
hold on
this stuff
child locks you know if you're
if you're a parent of a young child
you'll know what that's all about
this stuff is Magic it creates
a caramel ice cream that you just can't
recreate at home
smells so good
now first time I used this I just wasn't
paying attention and I used it as well
as the milk powder and that that's all
wrong because that's what it is it's
caramelized milk with sugar in it
use it instead of milk powder to create
a caramel ice cream and it's perfect
it's perfect caramel ice cream
shut my phone up
it's got a really nice smell the texture
is perfect it's got the right amount of
sweetness that is the best caramel ice
cream
I've had
the chocolate ice cream I've used a
lighter
fat content cocoa powder like I said
it's the brand is design
um
it's not I've gone for that one because
it's not quite as deep and Punchy
chocolate so if you're making chocolate
ice cream you want all that flavor but
when you're having something like this
you want to be careful that you have one
flavor doesn't overtake the others so
I've used a lighter fat cocoa
and it works perfectly well
nice little chocolate flecks in there
they're not too sweet they're not too
sharp they're really really good that
caramel ping that caramel is still
really soft glucose syrup
that is what's done that
and it is
after all this time
you can just be left with
oh I'm gonna eat that later
you're just left with all that goodness
yes cause our hard work
are they worth it I think so because it
ice cream is about The Whimsy and the
emotion of eating it it shouldn't just
be it's like a boring tub of one flavor
and scoop unless that's what your thing
is you don't like these multi-flavored
ice creams for me
I like to take a tub of ice cream and
and enjoy that emotion of going through
different things in the tub you know the
emotion of the caramel because it's
really sweet still really soft it's
silky it's smooth it's Heavenly the
caramel ice cream is really nice and it
sits on your tongue it lingers forever
the chocolate ice cream is sharper and
then you've got those bites of chocolate
in there as well
it's a perfect combination and thanks
again for our subscriber and hit me up a
DM on Instagram to request this flavor
it's been on my radar for a while I've
just not got around to doing it so I'm
really really glad that I was pushed to
do it so give this one a try
don't leave your ice cream to freeze
overnight before you do the core
don't forget to like And subscribe I'll
see you next time
[Music]